<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>The tragicall and lamentable historie of two faythfull mates Ceyx kynge of Thrachine, and Alcione his wife: dravven into English meeter. By W. Hubbard. 1569</title>
            <author>Hubbard, William.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1569</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 15 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 9 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-04">2011-04 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A03777</idno>
            <idno type="STC">STC 13897</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC S118887</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99854094</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">99854094</idno>
            <idno type="VID">19501</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A03777)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 19501)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1475-1640 ; 513:09)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>The tragicall and lamentable historie of two faythfull mates Ceyx kynge of Thrachine, and Alcione his wife: dravven into English meeter. By W. Hubbard. 1569</title>
                  <author>Hubbard, William.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>[16] p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>By Wyllyam How, for Richard Iohnes and are to be solde at his shop vnder the Lotterie house,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>Imprinted at London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>[1569]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>In verse.</note>
                  <note>Adapted from Ovid--STC.</note>
                  <note>Signatures: A.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of the original in the Bodleian Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2009-01</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-02</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-08</date>
            <label>Lauren Proux</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-08</date>
            <label>Lauren Proux</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-09</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:19501:1"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:19501:1"/>
            <p>
               <hi>The Tragicall</hi> and lamentable Hiſtorie of two faythfull Mates: <hi>Ceyx</hi> Kynge of Thrachine, and <hi>ALCIONE</hi> his wife: <hi>dravven into Engliſh</hi> Meeter.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>By W. Hubbard. 1569.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>JMPRINTED at London, by Wyllyam</hi> How, for Richard Iohnes and are to be ſolde at his <hi>ſhop vnder the Lotterie</hi> houſe.</p>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="poem">
            <pb facs="tcp:19501:2" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:19501:2"/>
            <head>
               <hi>The Tragicall and</hi> lamentable Hiſtorie of <hi>Ceyx</hi> and <hi>Alcione.</hi>
            </head>
            <lg>
               <l>WHen frowning Fortune gan aſſaulte</l>
               <l>her Foes: whoſe deth ſhe doth deſire</l>
               <l>She will reuenge, though for no faulte,</l>
               <l>When Enuie hath her ſet on fire:</l>
               <l>Shee ſeekes to bring men to decaie</l>
               <l>whom erſt alofte:</l>
               <l>She had ſet vp at pleaſant ſtaye,</l>
               <l>though reeling ofte.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>And then at laſt they tumbling downe</l>
               <l>from higheſt ſtaie, to loweſt ſtep:</l>
               <l>To lamentacion from Renowne,</l>
               <l>with tumbling caſt they downwarde lep,</l>
               <l>Amonge all other, one I finde</l>
               <l>vnfortunate:</l>
               <l>For at his ſtate, Fortune repinde</l>
               <l>with cruell hate.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>He was ſomtime of <hi>Thracine</hi> King,</l>
               <l>And <hi>CEYX</hi> I reade he had to name:</l>
               <l>Dame Fortune his miſchaunce ſeeking</l>
               <l>ſhe tolde him ſtreight by flickering Fame</l>
               <l>
                  <pb facs="tcp:19501:3"/>How <hi>Peleus</hi> his brother was</l>
               <l>by ruinous chaunce,</l>
               <l>With Death diſtroyed, as cam to paſſe,</l>
               <l>by Fortunes Launce.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>Whereat he muſing ſtoode diſmayde,</l>
               <l>and vexed ſore then in his thought:</l>
               <l>How eaſely might the ſignes he ſaide,</l>
               <l>the which before his death were wrought</l>
               <l>Of all men well perceiued be,</l>
               <l>as came to paſſe,</l>
               <l>Betokening this his deſtinie,</l>
               <l>which fearefull was.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>When <hi>CEYX</hi> the matter did perceiue,</l>
               <l>miſdoubting what was beſt to doo:</l>
               <l>He did deuiſe where he might haue,</l>
               <l>a remedie to ſlake his woo:</l>
               <l>For counſell he to ſéeke with ſpéede</l>
               <l>at Sacred <hi>SPELS,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Deuiſeth thus, as I do reade,</l>
               <l>where this God dwels.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>The God of <hi>CLAROS</hi> I do meane,</l>
               <l>where as an Oracle woulde tell,</l>
               <l>Eache thing to fill fonde fanſies ſtreame,</l>
               <l>but no good counſell their did dwell:</l>
               <l>
                  <pb facs="tcp:19501:3"/>Kinge <hi>CEYX</hi> diſpoſed thus to goe,</l>
               <l>to this fonde God:</l>
               <l>Dame Fortune hath prouided loe,</l>
               <l>this ſcorging Rod.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>He had a wife who had to name,</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>ALCIONE</hi> then Thrachine Quéene:</l>
               <l>She was a wife of paſſyng fame,</l>
               <l>few ſuch at this time can be ſeene:</l>
               <l>To whom he minded to diſcloſe,</l>
               <l>all his intente,</l>
               <l>Vnto his louing Mate he goes,</l>
               <l>vntimely ſent.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>He then began with faultring voice,</l>
               <l>to ſhewe the matter to his wife,</l>
               <l>At whoſe preſence ſhe did reioyce,</l>
               <l>for ſure ſhee loued him as her life,</l>
               <l>But when ſhe heard he would departe,</l>
               <l>with feare there ſtrake:</l>
               <l>A chilnes ſtraighte vnto hir hart</l>
               <l>that teares out brake.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>Thre times ſhe then about to ſpeake,</l>
               <l>thre times ſhe waſht hir face with teares</l>
               <l>Thre times ſhe of from teares did breake,</l>
               <l>and thus complained in his eares,</l>
               <l>
                  <pb facs="tcp:19501:4"/>What fault of myne (O Huſbande deare)</l>
               <l>doth thee compell?</l>
               <l>That thou wilt dwell no longer heere,</l>
               <l>but go to <hi>SPELL.</hi>
               </l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>Do Iorneies long delight thee nowe?</l>
               <l>or doth mine abſence better pleaſe</l>
               <l>Then my preſence? then I vowe</l>
               <l>to <hi>NEPTVNE,</hi> Guider of the Seas</l>
               <l>Whoſe Stormes vncertein thou muſt bide</l>
               <l>in wofull plight:</l>
               <l>To offer Giftes if he will guide</l>
               <l>thy Ship aright.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>Vntill thou comſt at wiſſhed Port:</l>
               <l>For ſure my care is great for thee,</l>
               <l>Thou art my Ioye and ſure comfort,</l>
               <l>my faithfull Spouſe geue eare to mée:</l>
               <l>Shall I haue cauſe onely to mourne?</l>
               <l>And ſhall my care</l>
               <l>Of thy vncerteine home returne</l>
               <l>be voide of feare?</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>The Sea doth make mee ſore afraide</l>
               <l>to thinke on it, my Corps doth quake,</l>
               <l>My minde with muſing is diſmaide,</l>
               <l>for verie woe my Ioinctes do ſhake:</l>
               <l>
                  <pb facs="tcp:19501:4"/>For broken late vpon the ſhoare</l>
               <l>the Ribbes of Ships</l>
               <l>I ſawe, whoſe Maſters long before</l>
               <l>the waues in whips.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>But yet my Spouſe, if that thy will</l>
               <l>I can by no entreatance moue:</l>
               <l>But that thou wilt perſeuer ſtyll,</l>
               <l>Conſider then my tender loue,</l>
               <l>And mée deare Huſbande) with thée take</l>
               <l>that I maye bee</l>
               <l>Partaker of thy griefe, and make</l>
               <l>ſome mirth for thee.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>O louing Wife <hi>ALCIONE,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>my Loue, my deare and onely ioye</l>
               <l>(Quoth he) and wept full tenderlye:</l>
               <l>Let not mine abſence thée annoye:</l>
               <l>Content thy ſelfe full quietlie,</l>
               <l>And will no more</l>
               <l>On houering waues to go with mée</l>
               <l>from Thrachine ſhoare.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>For my Returne ſhalbe againe</l>
               <l>if that the Goddes permit me life,</l>
               <l>Within two Monthes I tell thee plaine,</l>
               <l>as thou art my eſpouſed wife;</l>
               <l>
                  <pb facs="tcp:19501:5" rendition="simple:additions"/>With that ſhe gan for ioy to weepe,</l>
               <l>that <hi>CEYX</hi> had,</l>
               <l>Appointed daies and ſighed deepe,</l>
               <l>and wexed glad.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>She there doth bring him to the Shoore,</l>
               <l>Where he his laſt farewell did take,</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>ALCIONES,</hi> hart miſgaue before,</l>
               <l>ſhe did with trembling ioyntes oft quake,</l>
               <l>And ſtraining <hi>CEYX</hi> in her armes,</l>
               <l>with pittious looke,</l>
               <l>Her laſt farewell miſtruſting harmes,</l>
               <l>ſhe ſadly tooke.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>And when ſhe ſawe the watermen,</l>
               <l>the Ship beginne to driue from ſhore,</l>
               <l>And that ſhe muſt hir ſpouſe leaue then,</l>
               <l>ſhe muche more heauy then before,</l>
               <l>My only ioy is gon ſhe ſayd,</l>
               <l>why do I liue?</l>
               <l>Let death of thine, with mine be paide,</l>
               <l>I would it giue.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>And caſting vp hir waterie eies,</l>
               <l>ſhe did beholde her huſband ſtand,</l>
               <l>On Hatches gon now far on Seas,</l>
               <l>ſhe ſawe him becking with his hand:</l>
               <l>
                  <pb facs="tcp:19501:5"/>And ſhe like wiſe her hands did ſhake,</l>
               <l>as loue did moue,</l>
               <l>Where as ſhe did her laſt ſight take,</l>
               <l>of hir deere loue.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>And when the Ship was out of ſight,</l>
               <l>ſhe ſtraight vnto hir Chamber went,</l>
               <l>She ſcreeked out with maine and might,</l>
               <l>and pitiouſly ſhe did lament,</l>
               <l>She caſt her body on her bed,</l>
               <l>with ſory hart,</l>
               <l>With dumped ſprites as heauy as Led,</l>
               <l>renewes hir ſmart.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>And whilſt ſhe lieth muſing here,</l>
               <l>a pleaſant gale of winde doth blowe,</l>
               <l>The wether waxeth very cleare,</l>
               <l>theſe ſhipmen now in Seas do rowe,</l>
               <l>And <hi>CEYX</hi> doth make his men vp hale,</l>
               <l>the higheſt maſt,</l>
               <l>And ſet them vp with the top ſaile,</l>
               <l>that no wind waſt.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>At laſt they all ariued are,</l>
               <l>when night was com and day was ſpent,</l>
               <l>Where eche of them muſt ende their care:</l>
               <l>and eke muſt there, their liues relent,</l>
               <l>
                  <pb facs="tcp:19501:6"/>For <hi>BOREAS</hi> with his bitter blaſts</l>
               <l>doth fierſlie blow:</l>
               <l>And waues do riſe vp all in haſte</l>
               <l>to ouerthrowe</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>Their ſhip and they with fearefull ſpeede</l>
               <l>do cut down Sailes, &amp; Clothes down rend</l>
               <l>Eche man is buſie nowe at neede,</l>
               <l>Yet all in vaine thei do contend:</l>
               <l>For now the Tempeſt hath by force</l>
               <l>the vpper hande:</l>
               <l>King <hi>CEYX</hi> doth oftimes wiſh his Corſe</l>
               <l>to be on lande.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>With his deare Loue <hi>ALCIONE</hi>
               </l>
               <l>who now he ſaith, did warning geue</l>
               <l>Of foming Tempeſts of the Sea,</l>
               <l>yet he as then would not beleue:</l>
               <l>But willinglie would forwarde goe</l>
               <l>to ſeeke Counſell,</l>
               <l>To paſſe the Sea would forwarde rowe</l>
               <l>to go to <hi>SPELL.</hi>
               </l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>King <hi>CEYX</hi> did of his Loue ſtill ſpeake,</l>
               <l>he alwaies cried <hi>(ALCIONE,)</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Nothing would make his tonge of breake</l>
               <l>but wicked waues of watrie Sea</l>
               <l>
                  <pb facs="tcp:19501:6"/>When thus with Death he conquered was</l>
               <l>and diynge in Sea:</l>
               <l>He ſeemde to ſpeake halfe dead (alas)</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>ALCIONE.</hi>
               </l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>Whilſte <hi>CEYX</hi> doth lye thus in the Sea:</l>
               <l>quite drownde with ouer gulfing waues</l>
               <l>On rufull Bed <hi>ALCIONE</hi>
               </l>
               <l>with weeping eies, ſhe reſtles craues</l>
               <l>For ſafe and ſpeedie comming home</l>
               <l>of <hi>CEYX</hi> her Mate:</l>
               <l>Who lieth toſt on ſalt Sea fome,</l>
               <l>vnfortunate.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>Now dead and drowned in the Sea,</l>
               <l>yet ſhe the dayes doth compt and tell,</l>
               <l>She thinkes poore wretch <hi>ALCIONE,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>her huſbandes home returne from <hi>SPELL</hi>
               </l>
               <l>To be but ſlowe: and ſhe doth thinke,</l>
               <l>eche hower a day,</l>
               <l>No ioyes into her hart can ſink,</l>
               <l>for his delay.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>She hopeth yet to ſee him againe</l>
               <l>aliue at his appointed hower:</l>
               <l>Her expectacion was in vaine,</l>
               <l>for Fortune was diſpoſed to lower,</l>
               <l>
                  <pb facs="tcp:19501:7" rendition="simple:additions"/>On him poore wretch as late befell,</l>
               <l>yet ſhe doth make,</l>
               <l>Acompt of his returne from <hi>SPELL</hi>
               </l>
               <l>her louing make.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>The Lady being thus mindfull ſtill,</l>
               <l>of her owne ſpouſe and huſband deare</l>
               <l>The day is paſt the night doth fill,</l>
               <l>eche thing with darkenes bright &amp; cleare,</l>
               <l>And ſhe to reſtles Bed is gon,</l>
               <l>to take hir ſleepe</l>
               <l>And ſtraight a ſlumber ſtealing on,</l>
               <l>her eyes yet weepe:</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>This wofull wight <hi>ALCIONE,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>doth dreame ſhe ſeeth ſtand by her Bed,</l>
               <l>Her only ioy late drownd in Sea,</l>
               <l>pale, wan, ſtarke nakt, and cold as lead,</l>
               <l>She thought he leaned on her breſt,</l>
               <l>and to her ſaid,</l>
               <l>My louing wife me thou knoweſt,</l>
               <l>be not diſmaid.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>Thy <hi>CEYX</hi> is dead, therfore in vaine</l>
               <l>of my retourne no reckening make,</l>
               <l>The boiſterous windes with might &amp; main</l>
               <l>our ſhip on Seas did toſſe and ſhake,</l>
               <l>
                  <pb facs="tcp:19501:7"/>Vntill it was turnd vpſidowne,</l>
               <l>and drownd in Sea,</l>
               <l>O worthie wight of high renowne,</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>ALCIONE,</hi>
               </l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>Thou heareſt not by falſe reporte,</l>
               <l>but I my ſelfe my ſhipwreke ſhow,</l>
               <l>Ariſe therfore come and comfort</l>
               <l>thy huſband, and ſom teares beſtowe</l>
               <l>Vpon thy ſpouſe, and decke the now</l>
               <l>with moorning wéede,</l>
               <l>For I can mirth no more allowe,</l>
               <l>now I am dead.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>With that ſhe ſtretched forth her handes,</l>
               <l>her huſbands Ghoſt for to imbrace,</l>
               <l>He ſteps a ſide and backward ſtands,</l>
               <l>with that the teares ran downe hir face</l>
               <l>ſhe ſcreeketh out, why doeſt thou flie?</l>
               <l>and leaue me alone,</l>
               <l>Then take me with thee, for I muſt die,</l>
               <l>if thou art gon.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>All this ſhe did yet being a ſleape,</l>
               <l>and by and by ſhe did awake,</l>
               <l>And rewfully began to wéepe,</l>
               <l>and heauely the matter take:</l>
               <l>
                  <pb facs="tcp:19501:8"/>Shee rent her Clothes, and fare her heere,</l>
               <l>with extreme woe:</l>
               <l>Her Nurce then roſe with rewfull feare</l>
               <l>and ranne her to.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>She did demaunde what was the cauſe</l>
               <l>of her great griefe and piteous mone</l>
               <l>Wherat this Ladie yet did pauſe</l>
               <l>at laſt ſhe ſaide, I am vndone,</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>ALCIONE</hi> is caſt awaye</l>
               <l>with <hi>CEYX</hi> his death:</l>
               <l>For he hath yelded vp I ſaye</l>
               <l>his vitall breath.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>This, this, it is that I did feare</l>
               <l>before thy Iorney in my minde:</l>
               <l>I warned thee, thou didſt not care,</l>
               <l>That thou ſhouldſt not truſt to the winde</l>
               <l>And whilſt ſhe talked, the night was gone,</l>
               <l>and Daye was bright:</l>
               <l>Vnto the ſhoare with ſpeede ſhe ronne</l>
               <l>and footeſteppes light.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>She ſtanding mourning on the ſhoare,</l>
               <l>and caſting vp her weeping eies</l>
               <l>And liſtening how the Sea did roare</l>
               <l>a great waie of, on Sea ſhe ſpies</l>
               <l>
                  <pb facs="tcp:19501:8"/>A thing come tumbling on the Sea</l>
               <l>muche like a Corce,</l>
               <l>She meruailed what it ſhould bee</l>
               <l>that waters force</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>Brought houering ſo toward the ſhoare,</l>
               <l>at laſt ſhee ſawe, it was a man:</l>
               <l>She knewe not who it was therfore,</l>
               <l>To ſpeake ſhe then with woe began,</l>
               <l>Alas poore wretch (ſhe ſaid) thy wife</l>
               <l>if any there bee,</l>
               <l>Maye wiſh her ſelfe deuoyde of life</l>
               <l>for Death of thee.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>And as the Winde, the waues did toſſe,</l>
               <l>the Bodie floated nearer lande</l>
               <l>Yet ſhe not ware of her great loſſe</l>
               <l>Vntill it came vnto her hande,</l>
               <l>Anone it did arryue on ſhoare:</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>ALCIONE</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Sawe <hi>CEYX</hi> who grieued her full ſore</l>
               <l>late drownde in Sea.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>And therwithall ſhe ſcratched her face,</l>
               <l>her Heere and Garments ſhe did teare</l>
               <l>She reached out in wofull caſe</l>
               <l>to <hi>CEYX</hi> her tremblyng handes w<hi rend="sup">t</hi> feare</l>
               <l>
                  <pb facs="tcp:19501:9"/>She ſayde now comſt thou home my loue,</l>
               <l>in ſuch a caſe:</l>
               <l>He beyng dead, ſhe did remoue</l>
               <l>to touche his face.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>And alſo yet not being content,</l>
               <l>this wretched wight <hi>ALCIONE,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>She <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ieth D' <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>tropos conſent,</l>
               <l>and caſt her ſelfe into the Sea<g ref="char:punc">▪</g>
               </l>
               <l>And on her huſbands corce doth <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap>,</l>
               <l>as Poets faine:</l>
               <l>And both were turned to <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 span">
                     <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                  </gap>
               </l>
               <l>and ſtill remaine.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>Their loue right well we may <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap>
               </l>
               <l>for few ſuch Mates are at this day:</l>
               <l>Who loue ſo ſtedfaſt to the ende,</l>
               <l>Therfore e<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="4 letters">
                     <desc>••••</desc>
                  </gap>le take we may,</l>
               <l>By <hi>CEYX</hi> and <hi>ALCIONE.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>which both liue ſtill,</l>
               <l>As I do read and haunt the Sea,</l>
               <l>as Poets will,</l>
            </lg>
            <q>Faelix quem fa<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> 
               <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> Cantum.</q>
            <trailer>FINIS</trailer>
            <pb facs="tcp:19501:9"/>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
